Guide to the Charles H. Huberich Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles H. Huberich papers
1860-1906
SC0296
Huberich, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1877-1945
Huberich, Charles Henry,, 1877-1945.
4.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer from Stanford Law School, 1967.
Information about Access
None.
BIOGRAPHY
Charles Henry Huberich was born on February 18, 1877 in Toledo, Ohio. He grew up in San Antonio, Texas, where he studied under private tutors. Huberich received his undergraduate degree from the University of Texas at Austin in 1897 and his Master of Law degree a year later from the same institution. After receiving his Master of Civil Law degree from Yale in 1899, Huberich spent a few months studying at the Universities of Berlin and Heidelberg.
In 1900, he was elected as an instructor in law and political science by regents of the University of Texas at Austin. During his stay in Austin, he met Laura King Orr. They were married on June 11, 1902. They had one daughter, May Bess. Huberich taught at the University of Texas until he resigned in May 1905. Later that year, he received a Doctor of Laws degree from the University of Heidelberg and he accepted a teaching position at Stanford University.
Huberich taught Constitutional Law, Criminal Law and Conflict of Laws at Stanford until 1912. He was an assistant professor from 1905-1906, an associate professor during 1907, and a professor from 1907 to 1912. Huberich was also a professor of law at the University of Chicago during the 1907 summer session, and at the University of Wisconsin from 1909-1910.
After leaving Stanford, Huberich made his home in New York and he set up law offices both there and in London. On July 15, 1925, Huberich was married for the second time, this time to Princess Nina Mdivani. Charles Huberich died at the age of 68 on June 18, 1945.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The papers of Charles H. Huberich include correspondence, photographs, postcards, calling cards, cartes-des-visites, and miscellaneous material. The correspondence, which is mainly in German, includes letters to and from Charles Huberich (1895-1906) and correspondence of Huberich's parents (1860's to 1900's). Other items in the collection include invitations, certificates, law examination, a poem, Huberich's wedding announcement, and newsclippings in English and German.
Access Terms
Huberich, Charles Henry,, 1877-1945.; Stanford University. School of Law. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; German Americans--Texas.
Collection Contents
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters from C.H. Huberich, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, through 1895 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1900-1903 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Letters to C.H. Huberich, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence of C.H. Huberich's parents (excluding correspondence with CHH), 1860s (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Parents' correspondence, 1870s (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Parents' correspondence, 1880s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Parents' correspondence, 1890s (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Parents' correspondence, 1900s (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Parents' correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Letters from Mrs. C.H. Huberich (Lollie) to CHH's parents (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Letters (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Unidentified photographs (Box 3, Folder 1-13)
- Miscellaneous Material (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 2 invitations: one to Ashville Literary Society and the other to meet the members of the Academy of Science
  - 2 certificates - both in German
  - mid-year examination in Criminal Law, 1905 Dec 18
  - poem - written in German
  - CHH and Lollie's wedding announcement and newspaper clippings re the wedding
- Newspaper Clippings - in English and German (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ambrotype Photograph (unidentified); 2 small notebooks; decorated box filled with slips of paper - some with notes on them (written in German); printed book with notes written on it (both in German) (Box 4)
- Postcards - empty; from CHH to parents; to CHH; and to CHH's parents (Box 5)
- Calling cards (Box 6)
- Cartes-des-Visites (unidentified) (Box 7)
- Cartes-des-Visites (unidentified) (Box 8)